<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Vikram Sharma Mailthody</title>
    <link>https://msharmavikram.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vikram Sharma Mailthody</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Vikram Sharma Mailthody</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topics for Masters (MTECH) in VLSI</title>
      <link>https://msharmavikram.github.io/post/mtech_project_ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msharmavikram.github.io/post/mtech_project_ideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VLSI is a very vast domain and you can put anything as research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, VLSI can be classified under multiple major categories like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Front end digital design for a problem (Simulation or emulation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EDA algorithm development or improvement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend -physical implementation or design rule optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STA simplification and DFT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High performance Transistor designing and modelling- front end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fabrication - Material design and equipment design for manufacturing
Each of the above ones have large number of applications and problems which are yet to solved and lot of researchers working for the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better computer architecture for enhanced bus arbitration to reduce cache hit miss or better throughput, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing time complexity of EDA tool or development of the same for latest technology node or new material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DRC automation to check quality and also improvise congestion in full chip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timing optimization for DFT implementation (Lot of time is spent on checking quality of chip post fabrication)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5G or 4G LTE needs high throughput, low power, high frequency transistors which are not possible with just Silicon based ones. Compounds are added to resolve the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality assurance to manufacturing equipment… You can have many here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As stated in point 5, new materials are needed to enhance performance of traditional transistors. (Also Moore’s law is reaching it tipping point… Still long way to go but research in direction to replace have been proposed - GaN is a example.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just named a examples in each categories. If you need more, please explore it in IEEE Xplore or IEEE Spectrum or VLSI Design and ReUse sites. All these provides good information on latest developments around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topics in Computer Architecture</title>
      <link>https://msharmavikram.github.io/post/latest_research_in_computer_architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msharmavikram.github.io/post/latest_research_in_computer_architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The below list is not complete. Further it is a first draft. I will be adding links to good papers and reference materials over a period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent advancements in computer architecture :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accelerators (FPGA, GPU, ASIC.. )
a. Latency critical application accelerators - like networking, financial algorithms, etc
b. Crypto-currency or accelerators for block-chain
c. DNA sequencing - lot of applications need accelerations here and each one require unique methodologies
d. HLS based synthesis and parameters tuning algorithms for accelerator IPs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning Architecture (Includes autonomous driving, IOT…)
a. Generalized inference architecture for DeepLearning
b. Reduction of power, compute and area for deep learning accelerator
c. Specialized sparse matrix architecture
d. Distributed NoC based architecture for ML
e. Hardware-Software co-designed for NLP, Image and Video recognitions
f. Functional Safety architecture for autonomous driving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Von Neumann Architecture
a. Near Memory Computing architecture (this will get back to 80s if succeeds…!)
b. 3D stack Memory architecture (check Architecture 2030 report)
c. 2.5D stack Memory architecture
d. Compute in future memory architecture like Memristor, HMC, MLC NAND, etc
e. Asynchronous architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silicon Photonics
a. Silicon - Photonics integration
b. New network topology - revisiting crossbar, delta, ring, mesh, torus- all required. (Because of Wavelength-Division multiplexing scheme. )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heterogeneous computer architecture
a. Coherence and consistency between FPGA cache, GPU and CPU in heterogeneous architecture
b. Distributed versus local HPC designs (NUMA, NoC etc)
c. Graph analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure computing or Crypto-computing or block-chain
a. Random number generator (Yes, there is no true random number generator yet)
b. Secure computing of sensory inputs in pipeline stages (IF, D, E, M, W and should handle context switches, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human computer interactions
a. Connecting to brain or increasing the capacity of brain
b. Augmented/Virtual reality - Motion tracking, image rendering, image merging, etc
c. Speech recognition in noisy environment
d. Low power always on recognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Computing architecture
a. Check Architecture - 2030 report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radical architecture
a. Quantum Computing (I think this is totally open - Full stack needs to be redesigned with QC - Check Architecture 2030 report)
b. DNA computing
   i.  Storage of data in DNA
   ii. Fast read/write pipeline architecture for DNA computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reference:&lt;/strong&gt;
1. Future directions- Architecture 2030 @ ISCA. &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/pape..&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/pape..&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updated 19 Nov 2017: Topics
&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know i have done poor job on grouping and naming- anyways it a first draft. So I am fine. Will fix it eventually.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will also add links and couple of papers that sound interesting in these topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The list that I will populating will be based on my experience, reading, listening and interacting. If you have good topics and need to be added to this post, please shoot a message to me! Will be happy to add.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
